Hi I'm Bob Tabor and in this series of videos,
over 75 videos,
I'm going to demonstrate how to build apps
that can be sold or downloaded for free on the Windows Store
for Windows desktop, or phone,
or wherever Universal Windows Platform apps can be used.
Which will soon include devices like the Xbox One,
Microsoft Hub, and even the HoloLens.
Now that term Universal Windows Platform I just used
it describes tools and APIs that you can utilize
to build apps that run universally
across all new Windows devices.
And the beauty is that you can write one application
and it'll look great on many different screen resolutions
and device form factors.
And really that's one of the most important things
that I'm going to discuss and demonstrate
in this series of lessons.
So this series is intended for an absolute
beginner audience.
Having said that, you should already have some familiarity
with C# and Visual Studio.
And I want to assume that you're watching this after
making sure that you've either watched or at least
you understand all the concepts that I discuss in
the C# fundamentals for absolute beginners series
on Microsoft Virtual Academy in channel nine.
You can find it at this URL on the screen.
Now if you're already an experienced developer
then -- fair warning -- quite honestly here,
this course is going to move very slow for you.
And we did that on purpose.
And honestly there's probably some better resources
out there where you can spend your time.
I'd recommend that you watch Andy Wigley and Shen Chauhan
in a series that they created called
a developers guide to Windows 10.
Great, up to date, it's awesome.
And I'd recommend you start there
if you're already an experienced developer.
Now this is the fourth version of this particular video
series that I've created.
And I started way back on the Windows Phone 7
in about 2009 / 2010.
Each time that I release a version of this series
I'm asked a few questions repeatedly.
So I want to answer those right up front
so that there's no misunderstanding.
First of all, you must use Windows 10
to build apps for Windows 10,
to build Universal Windows Platform apps.
You cannot use Windows 8.1, or Windows 8,
or Windows 7, or Windows XP.
Alright, you have to use Windows 10, that's number one.
Number two, you have to use Visual Studio 2015.
Now I recommend that you use
Visual Studio 2015 Community Edition,
which is a free edition with all the features of Pro edition
but it's intended for individuals who are just learning
or creating a community based projects.
Now frankly you can use other editions of Visual Studio
but not previous versions.
You must use version 2015 to build
Universal Windows Platform apps, that's number two.
Number three, you're going to see me use the phone emulator
in order to run and test my applications occasionally.
It'll look like a little phone running on my screen
with a little menu off to the right hand side.
It's actually running software called Hyper-V
which is a platform for running virtual machines
on your desktop.
And so it's running the Windows Phone 10 operating system
in a little virtual machine that looks like a phone.
Now you might need special hardware
to run the phone emulator.
Specifically your motherboard and your chip
must support a technology called SLAT,
or rather "Second Level Address Translation".
Now most modern motherboards will support this,
however not all motherboards and chips support this.
Most importantly, I can't help you with this.
I understand very little about it.
If you get errors during install of Visual Studio 2015
then you can search Microsoft's forums for help,
but again I can't help you.
I've tried to help in the past and honestly I've
probably confused more people than I've actually helped.
Now the worst case scenario if you can't get
the emulator running on your local machine,
is that you might need to deploy your apps
to a physical phone device running
either the full edition or a beta edition of Windows
Phone 10 for the purpose of testing.
It's simple to do,
however I don't demonstrate how to do that
in this series of videos.
There are articles online that'll show you how.
Now if you have all these things in place
then, number four, you're going to need to
turn on Developer Mode.
And the way that you get that is you open up Settings
in Windows 10 and you go to Update & Security.
And then on the left hand side you select For Developers,
and make sure to choose Developer mode.
And if it asks you to save then go ahead and save.
I'm not sure, I can't remember that particular part.
But make sure that you have that set.
Visual Studio will probably give you an error
if you first run an application if you don't
have that setting set up, okay?
Now this series of videos
is about 15 or 16 hours long, it's fairly comprehensive.
And one of the most important new features
of this training series is that I'm going to give you
homework assignments called challenges.
And I'll give you all the tools that you need
to build an app to my specifications
and then I'm even going to give you the solution
to the challenge in the form of a video
in case you get stuck.
And that's a great way for you,
and you should definitely do these challenges
where you "get your hands dirty in the code"
as I like to say it.
We're also going to build a little cheat sheet
for review purposes,
and then you can reference it after you finish
the series of videos.
Feel free to add to the cheat sheet
anything that you think might be useful
as you go forward and start building your own applications.
And then finally in the last half of the series,
we're going to build four entire applications
and even one of them for inclusion in the Windows Store.
Now these apps are going to show you
how to think like an app developer
from concept through implementation.
And we'll use a variety of different techniques, and APIs,
and tools and approaches to learn how to
interact with sensors on a given device.
How to access media libraries,
how to access online services that provide weather updates.
And even allow us to tap into fun services
like Marvel comics web API,
that allow us to retrieve back all their characters
and look through them and look through the artwork.
Now many of the videos in the series will have a zip file
associated with them that contains the code
that I wrote while recording the video.
Or in the case of challenges like I just described
a moment ago,
it'll contain the images that you need, any instructions,
or any other files that'll be required
in order to actually perform that challenge.
Now the file will be on the page
where you're currently watching the video,
or where you originally downloaded the video from.
So please before you ask in the comments,
"I can't find the download link,
where's the download link, the download link!"
Please hit Control + f on your keyboard in your web browser
and search for the term "download".
If there's no link to download a file
then that particular video does not have files to download.
Please search for the term download first.
Now while this is a very inclusive set of videos
I mean 15 to 16 hours is a lot of content to go through.
This is still really just an introduction.
I can't possibly show you everything
that the Universal Windows Platform contains.
You should treat this as a gentle introduction only,
but you should always refer back to
Microsoft's own documentation at the Windows Dev Center
for comprehensive explanation
how to get the most out of Universal Windows Platform.
And you can access that at http://dev.windows.com
Now remember that you can't just watch
a screen cast tutorial training series
the way that you would watch a movie or a sitcom on TV.
You're going to need to become an active learner.
Don't be afraid to rewind or even rewatch an entire video
or a portion of the video if at first
something doesn't really make a lot of sense to you.
Or look at the documentation at the Windows Dev Center
at the link I just shared with you.
For more details surrounding the given topic
that we're discussing at that moment in the videos.
You learn best whenever you use different
modalities to learn the same idea, the same content.
And ultimately the videos that I'm presenting are just
one tool to help you realize your aspirations
of building apps for sale in the Windows Store.
Now, on a personal note if you like what I do here
please visit me at
http://www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
where I help beginners get their
first software development job
building Windows and web apps
into world's best companies.
There are tons of challenge exercises there
and deeper insights into writing software using
Visual Studio, and C#, and ASP.NET and more.
Alright now finally I'd like to take a moment and thank
the hundreds of thousands of people who have watched
the previous versions of this series.
And for those who took the time to actually tell Microsoft
that you wanted more of this type of training.
Your feedback made this happen,
so thank you very much.
Also I want to thank Andy Wigley who patiently answered
all of the questions that I had and gave me a ton of advice
while I was building this series.
I'm very thankful for his guidance
as I worked on these lessons.
And ultimately this series was championed primarily
by Clint Rutkas who has been involved in almost all of the
video projects that I have worked on for Microsoft.
Without Clint, none of this would be possible.
So please reach out to him on Twitter
and let him know how much you appreciate his good work.
Okay so enough setup.
You've got Visual Studio 2015 running on Windows 10
and you've turned on Developer mode in Settings
like we looked at just a moment ago,
and you're wondering what comes next.
Well we're going to get started in the very next video.
We'll see you there.